Guide to the William W. Austin papers, 1947-1991.
Austin, William W. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William W. Austin papers, 1947-1991.
14-20-2297
Austin, William W.
10 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diaries, printed materials, research materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Subject files, diaries, and general correspondence pertaining to Austin's career. Also copy of his Ph.D. thesis, "Harmonic Rhythm in 20th-Century Music," from Harvard University, 1950; and files relating to his students including the composer Steve Reich.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Music.
William Weaver Austin (1920- ) has been professor of music history and appreciation at Cornell since 1947. He was chairman of the Music Department from 1958 to 1963 and also served as University organist.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Subject files, diaries, and general correspondence pertaining to Austin's career. Also copy of his Ph.D. thesis, "Harmonic Rhythm in 20th-Century Music," from Harvard University, 1950; and files relating to his students including the composer Steve Reich.
Includes music written by Austin for his wife for poems by A. R. Ammons, W. H. Auden, e. e. cummings, Phyllis McGinley, W. B. Yeats, and others.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Austin, William W.; Reich, Steve, 1936-; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Cornell University. Department of Music.
Subjects:
Music -- Instruction and study.; College teachers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 6-8 are restricted to permission of donor. Additionally the Steve Reich papers in Box 8 are restricted to permission of Mr. Reich.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Steve Reich
Lionel Wolberger
Boxes 1-5
Series II. Journal
Boxes 6-8
Series III. Articles, Notes, Teaching Materials, and Miscellany
Boxes 5 and 9
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Assorted Correspondence - A, 1961-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adams, R.M. "What was Modernism?" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adams, Bill, 1985-1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - F. Advisory C. on the Presidency - Confidential Records of Meetings, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Univ., 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Afro-American, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Amaldev, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ammons, 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Musicological Society, 1969-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Kinkeldey Prize, American Musicological Society, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Picker, American Musicological Society, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Temperley, American Musicological Society, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Archibald, 1979-1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Arts and Sciences, July 14, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Arts at Cornell, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Austin, William, "10 Contemporary Symphonies" (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Assorted Correspondence - B, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - B, 1967-1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Contains: Barker, D. 1967; Battersby 1975; Bell, Barbara 1976; Bent, M.; Bentzon, N.; Bishop, J.; Black, Max 1969; Blum, Steve 1982; Bonaventura, Mario 1970; Borroff, E. 1978; Borris, S. 1961; Boult 1962; Bower, Calvin 1982; Brook, Claire 1987
  - Bacon, Ray, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Baillie, Isobel, 1961-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Barbera, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Barbera, A., 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Barlow, John, "On Not Climbing Kilimanjaro" (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Barlow, John, 1971-1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bärtschi, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bartha, 1971-1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bauer, Ross, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Becker, Judith, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Beckwith, A.S., 1974-1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Beckwith, R.S., 1986-1994 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Benton, R., 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bergeron, Katherine, 1983-1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Berman, L., 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Binkerd, 1972-1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Binkerd, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Binkerd, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Black, Max, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Blazhkov, 1974-1981 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Blume, F., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bohlman, Philip, 1985-1993 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Boulez, Pierre, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Brill, Johnathan, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Brinkmann, R., 1970-1985 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Brown, Dan, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Brown, Howard M., 1967-1978 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Brill, Jonathan, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Brown, Malcolm - Writings, 1963-1983 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Budapest (IMC), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Buechner, Alan, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Burt, John G., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Burak, D., 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Assorted Correspondence - C, 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Carruth, Jack (John), 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Carruth, Jack (John), 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Carruth, Lee, 1972-1987 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Carruth, Jack (John), 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Cazden, N., 1972-1977 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Challis, John, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Chambure, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Chase, G., 1972-1987 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Christie, Edward, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Chihara, 1965-1975 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Chihara, 1979-1988 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Clarke, Henry, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Clarke, Henry, 1973-1983 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Clarke, Henry, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Clarke, Henry, 1933-1973 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Clarke, Associated, 1984-1990 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Clynes, M., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - College Music Society, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - To WA from College Music Society, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - From WA to College Music Society, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Concerning College Music Society, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - College Music Society, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Music Society, R. Douglas sec., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Music Society Symposium, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cornell Music Society, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Music Society, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - College Music Society, Salem, N.C., 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - College Music Society Bands, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - College Music Society, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - College Music Society, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Conte, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - College Music Society, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cowdery, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Craft, 1961-1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Curtis-Smith, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Danckert, W. Offprints, 1956-1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Craig, D., 1971-1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Assorted Correspondence - D, 1962-1978; Dadelsen, D. - 1962, de La Grange, H. - 1962, Dickinson, June - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Dahlhaus, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Damp, George, 1967-1984 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Dietz, R. on Blitzstein, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Assorted Correspondence - D, Before 1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Department, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Department, 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Department, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Department, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Department, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Department, July 1966- June 1967 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Deflein, Erich, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Drabkin, William, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Drozin, Garth, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Druskin, 1970-1990, 1971-1990 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Dustin, William, Sheet Music, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Eaton, Flack, Damace, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Eggebrecht, 1961-1977 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Eggebrecht, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Elias, Cathy, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Emerson, Caryl, 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Emerson, Kitsie, 1981-1991 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Epstein, Dena, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Department, Music, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Eschman, K., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Eshpai, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Evett, Robert, February 24, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - F. Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Falconer, Joan, 1965-1982 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Fassler, Margot, 1979-1995 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - 101-Attendence, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Falkner, Keith, 1959-1984 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Faure (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Feil, Hans C., 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Fellerer, 1948-1983 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Fellman, Philip, 1974-1986 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Fernandez, M., 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Fine, Irving, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - W.O. Fiske, "The Cornell Changes" (Piano Arrangement by J. Kirkpatrick) (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - French, R.F., 1961-1995 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Firm, Woody, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Follmer, David, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Forbes, E., 1959-1989 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Foster, 1960-1974 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Foster Reviews, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Foster, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Foster, Illinois, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Frid, G., 1978-1985 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Fried, Joshua, December 18, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Fromm, Paul, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - G. Correspondence, Before 1980 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Georgiades, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Greissle, Felix, March 15, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Fung, K., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - G. Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Godwin, J., 1978 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Godwin, J., 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Godwin, J., 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Godwin, J., 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Greene, Philip, 1978-1992 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Greene, Philip, 1976-1984 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Greene, Philip - Essays (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Grout, M.D., 1987-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Grout, April-May 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Grout, 1965-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Grout Reviews, 1968-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Grout, 1945-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - D.J. Grout-William Austin, 1951-1960 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Grout Festschrift, 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Gruber, Barry - Dissertation, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Gwilt (Hong Kong), 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Gushee, L., 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - H. Correspondence, 1965-1986; Hacker, Andrew, 1971; Halim, 1966; Halperin, Joan, 1976; Hamilton, David, 1972; Hartell, 1986; Hastings, Baird, 1972; Heins, Ernst, 1966; Hennenberg, Fritz, 1976-1977; Hilson, Gail, 1972; Hockett, 1981-1984; Hofman, Shomo, 1975; Holoman, Kern, 1978; Hordern, Diane, 1980; Hu, Victor, 1978; Huband, Daniel, 1985; Huggler, John, 1965; Hughes, Elizabeth (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Hamm, Ch., 1987-1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Hartell, John, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Hatch, 1983-1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Hatch, 1972-1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Heller, 1977-1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Jone, Hildegarde, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Hill, Christopher, 1980-1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Hilliard, John, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Hirsbrunner, Theo, 1975-1982 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Hitchcock, H. Wiley, 1973-1987 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Hindemith, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Hoffman, R., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Clarissa and Other Holloway (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Norton, 1962-1967 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Holloway, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Howat, 1982-1994 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Howlett, 1983-1993 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - J. Correspondence, Before 1980 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - J. Correspondence, 1968-1992 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Jackson, Barbara, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Janower, David, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Johnson, Hunter, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Josquin, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - K. Correspondence, Katz, Israel, 1976; Kelly, Kevin, 1982; Keren, Zui, 1980; Kirkpatrick, Ralph, 1976; Kmen, 1967; Kohn, Karl, 1967; Kohn, Karl, 1967; Kolb, Roger, 1973; Kraft, Leo, 1967; Kreter, Leo, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Krenek, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Kammen, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Kaufmann, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Kawai, Yoshiko, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Kerman, Joseph, 1966-1988 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Kernfeld, 1978-1989 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Kidd, James C. "Melodic Process in J.S. Bach's 'Goldberg Variations', 1980 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Kingman, 1979-1988 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Holloway, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Klausmeyer, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Kovnatskaya, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Krumhansl, 1984-1993 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - K.J. and Frisch, W., 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Keil, C., 1989 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Keck, Michael, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Kremlev, J., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Kuypers, J., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - L. Correspondence, Lane, Bill, 1978; Lang, Paul, 1966; Langner, Thomas, 1975; Ledbetter, Steven, 1983; Lee; Liess, Andreas, 1962; Lubin, Steve, 1974; Ludwig, Lester, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - L. Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Laade, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Lang, Paul, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Lange, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Langevin, Kenneth, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Leeuw, Ton de, 1967-1977 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Lehrman, Leonard J., 1978-1995 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Levy, Janet., 1965-1990 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Liess, Andreas, 1962-1967 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Liu, Clifton, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Lo, Vivien, 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Lo, Vivien, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Lockspeiser, Edward, 1963-1970 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Mendel, Arthur, 1962-1977 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Lockwood, Larry P., 1976-1989 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Longyear, Rey, 1990-1994 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Longyear, R.M., 1963-1968 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - M. Correspondence, Morales Bance, 1965-1966; Ming, James, 1966; Miller, Robert, 1986; Masselos, William, 1966; McAllester, Rita, 1962; Moore; Meyerowitz, Jan, 1972; Mohr, Ernst, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Macmillan, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Maegaard, 1972-1985 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Magnussen, Jon, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Marshall, Yale, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Mann, Alfred, 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - May, Daniel, 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - May, Stephen, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - McCredie, Andrew D., 1968-1979 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Mersmann, Hans, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Meylarh, Mirra, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Correspondence about NY Congress, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Middleton, Robert, 1963-1970 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Mingus, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Moldenhauer, Hans and Rosaleen, 1965-1980 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Monaco, 1970-1980 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Morales-Bance, Luis, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Morrill, Dexter, 1981-192 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Morris, Edward P., 1978-1985 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Murray, E., 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Musgrave, Thea, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - (About) M2OC, 1967-1973 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Morrill, Dexter, 1975-1980 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - N. Correspondence, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - N. Correspondence, Neal, Art, 1971; Nee, Thomas; Newman, Marion, 1979; Newman, William, 1971; Noske, Frits, 1971-1972; Nossen, Steffi, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Nancarrow, Conlon, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Newell, Robert, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - New York University, Institute of Audio Research (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Niemann, Edmund, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Norton, W.W., 1957-1962 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Norton, 1962-1967 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Nyman, Michael, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Ohl, John, 1973-1994 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Orlov, Henry, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Orlov, Henry, 1978-1988 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Orlov, Henry, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Oxford, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - P. Correspondence, 1965-1977; Pasley, Robert, 1977; Patrick, James, 1972; Perl, Adam, 1965; Pfrogner, Hermann, 1967; Pirrotta, 1968; Pommers, Leon, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Parakilas, 1983-1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Parks, Anne, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Payzant, Geoffrey - Selected Papers Concerning Hanslick (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Perlis, V., 1973-1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Parakilas, 1976-1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Piston, W.H., April 4, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Piston et al., 1947-1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Piston, W.H., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Pleasants, H., 1967-1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Pniewski, Tom, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Pollack, 1975-1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Poulenc, 1953-1965 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Ptobhakar, Vinay, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 213 Project, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Woodstock, Music 213, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - S. Correspondence, Slawson, Wanye, 1985; Snyder, Hugh W., 1982; Souvtchinsky, Pierre, 1962; Spector, Irwin, 1984-1985; Spring, Howard, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Sadie, Julie Anne (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Sahlein, 1962-1966 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Samuel, 1971-1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Shimizu Michinori, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - SJO Drafts, July 1986 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - SJO Draft September, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Spitzer, J., 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - R. Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Ratz, December 14, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - R. Correspondence, Radice, Mark, 1974; Ratz, Erwin, 1962; Riedel, Johannes, 170; Rijavec, 1982; Ringer, Alexander, 1974; Robinson, Earl; Rollin, Bob, 1972; Rosonstiel, Leonie, 1980; Rostropovich, Mstislav, 1978; Rothgeb, John, 1984; Rowell, Lewis, 1985; Rubsamen, Walter, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - SJO. Drafts, September-December 1986 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Randel, Don, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Ratner, Leonard, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Steve Reich
    - Correspondence, 1954-1968 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence and Performances, 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Performances, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence about Performances, Music, and Grants, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, Performance Posters, Articles, 1976-1978 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, Performances Papers, Articles, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - "Parabola", 1980 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, Performance, Articles, 11981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - About "Tehillim", 1985 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Paul Epstein on "Piano Phase", 1984 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, Performances, Articles, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Music, Reviews, and Articles, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Walsh, Mary Jane - Reich Interview, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Reviews, Music, and Biography, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Articles and Interviews, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Assorted Accounts on "The Cave" (by Reich, presumably), May 21-23, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Interviews and Articles on Upcoming Work, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Interviews, Notices from "The Cave", 1989-1994 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Notes and Reviews, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Richter, 1967-1981 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Richter, Lukos, 1972-1981 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Riss, Wendy, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Ritz, David, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Rochberg, G., 1952 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Rockefeller - Martha Baird Rockefeller Fund for Music, Inc., 1969-1974 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - RMP, 1951-1995 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Rogers, 1983-1995 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Romadinova, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - S. Correspondence, Before 1980 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Root, Deane L., 1983-1994 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Ross, B., 1979 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Schaeffner, Andre, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Seeger, Charles, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Seeger, Pete, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Scherchen, Hermann, November 14, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Schuh, May 25, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Schwarz,B., 1971-1984 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Shackford, Charles Reeve, 1973-1980 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Schneerson, Masha, 1972-1982 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Siegel, Elie, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Souvtchinsky, Piene, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - T. Correspondence, Before 1980 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Tappolet, Willy, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Taruskin, R., 1981-1988 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Tcherepnin, A., 1967-1977 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Temkin, Bruce S., 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Testimonials, 1948-1975 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Tick, Judith, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Tick, Judith (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Tilles, Nurit, 1986-1992 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Thieberger, Ed, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - "Types of Musical Taste Among Students", 1952 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Jurgen, Uhde, 1971-1981 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - USSR, November 1971-1980 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - USSUR (Trip Notes) (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - V. Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Van Tienhoven, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Vanese, Louise, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Velimirovie, Milos, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Vilardi, Kathy, 1978-1989 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Vinton, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Vinton, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - W. Correspondence, 1963-1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - W. Correspondence, Wachsmann, 1982; Wade, Bonnie, 1978; Weber, E., 1962; Weitz, M., 1972; Wiener, Philip, 1979; Wilbur, Richard, 1966; Wiley, John, 1977; Wiora; Wirth, 1962; Worley, Joh, 1967; Wright, Margaret, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Walker, John, 1981-1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - WHCU, 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Weissmann, J., 1968-1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Wellesz, February11, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Wenk, 1991-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Williams, Martin, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Williams, Martin, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Wenk, 1977-1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Wenk, Arthur, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Wenk, Arthur, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Wenk, Arthur, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Wenk, Arthur, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Wenk, Arthur, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Wenk, Arthur, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Wenk, Arthur, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Wenk, Arthur, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Wenk, Arthur, 1975-1980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Wenk, Arthur, October 1972-August 1975 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Wenk, Arthur, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Wenk, Arthur, Extracurr., 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Wildberger, Melvin, 1973-1980 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Williams, W.C., 1961 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Winslow, Richard, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Winslow, Richard, 1974-1982 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Lionel Wolberger
    - Wolberger, Creative Writing and Poetry Papers, and Notebooks, 1979-1981 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Creative Writing, Texts, Correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence, Notes, Drafts, 1985-1988 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - 'The Music of Argument: Issues in the Performance and Transmission of Talmud Chant," First Dissertation Draft" by Lionel Wolberger, June 30, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence and Articles on Music of Different Cultures, 1991-1994 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Worner, Karl H., 1966 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Yates, Peter, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Yung, Bell, 1980-1989 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - General Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - General Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Misc. Personal Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Misc. Official Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Dead Correspondence, up to 1954 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Letters Sent to Archives (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Series II. Journal
  - Journals, September-December 1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Journals, January-February 1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Journals, March-April 1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Journals, May-June 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Journals, July-August 1967 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Journals, September-November 1967 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Journals, December 1967-January 1968 (Box 6, Folder 7)